Ashraful Islam

Graduate Research Assistant at UAB aislam@uab.edu

github.com/ashraful-islam-rafi Java, C, C++, Python, Racket, PHP, JavaScript

Summary

Computer Science graduate student at the University of Alabama at Birmingham (UAB) with over 2 years of academic research experience and over 7 years of industry experience taking on roles such as Software Engineer, and Programmer.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ALABAMA AT BIRMINGHAM

Birmingham, USA Jan 2022 - Present

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Computer Science

o PI: Dr. Thomas Gilray, Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science, UAB

LEADING UNIVERSITY

Sylhet, Bangladesh

B. Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering

Aug 2009 - Aug 2013

EXPERIENCE

_		
•	UNIVERSITY OF ALABAMA AT BIRMINGHAM Graduate Research Assistant	Birmingham, USA Jan 2022 - Present
•	BANGLA SEARCH ENGINE (PIPILIKA) Software Engineer (Research and Development)	Sylhet, Bangladesh Aug 2017 - Mar 2021
•	SOUTHEAST UNIVERSITY Programmer	Dhaka, Bangladesh Apr 2015 - Aug 2017
•	IT LAB SOLUTIONS LTD. Software Developer	Sylhet, Bangladesh Sep 2013 - Dec 2014

SKILLS

- Languages: Java, C, C++, Python, Racket, PHP, JavaScript
- Databases/Frameworks/Technologies: Spring Boot, Java Servlet, Flask, Codeigniter, Jsoup, Scrapy, jQuery, Bootstrap3, AJAX, MySQL, MongoDB, Apache Solr, HTML5, CSS3
- Others: Git, Docker, AWS, Maven, WordPress, SDLC, STLC, MVC, Agile, Scrum, Waterfall, Linux, Windows, MacOS

Extracurricular / Activities

- Treasurer: Managed financial operations of the Bangladesh Student Association (BSA), a graduate student organization at UAB
- Judge: Served as a judge of the Summer 2023 Undergraduate Research Expo, UAB
- Tutor: Conducted over 15 programming workshops focused on Data Structures and Algorithms at Leading University, with each session attended by more than 40 students.
- Contest Participation: Competed in various national and inter-university programming contests, including IUT 4th National ICT Fest (2012), NSU ACM ICPC Dhaka Site (2011), SUST Inter-University Programming Contest (2011), and IUT Inter-University Programming Contest (2011)
- Public Relation Officer: Coordinated and managed 3 Intra-university programming contests for the Leading University Computer Club (LUCC)